Robert Neil Cole

613 W. Broadway Street • Lenoir City, TN 37771-2702 (865) 560-6051 • rncole@gmail.com

Objective

I am a senior civil design engineer with a Senior Reactor Operator Management Certification, more than five years experience in engineering design and corrective action program management, and more than ten years of information technology experience. I am seeking to utilize my unique skill-set and plant understanding in a supervisory or management role. Specific areas of interest include plant design, operations, and nuclear construction with opportunities to take on unique or challenging roles.

Professional Experience

2012–pres.

Senior Civil Design Engineer at Tennessee Valley Authority

Ensured engineering schedule adherence as a member of the Engineering Rapid Response Team at the Watts Bar Nuclear Plant by providing engineering expertise to Operations and other plant organizations. Primary responsibilities included production of design change requests, temporary alterations, and engineering input and oversight. Secondary responsibilities included continued ownership of Cranes and Rigging (including NUREG-0612, Control of Heavy Loads), representing Watts Bar and Engineering at Nuclear Regulatory Commission meetings related to flood mode at their head-quarters in Washington, DC, and support of IBM Cognos reports.

I was selected for a Pressurized Water Reactor Senior Reactor Operator Certification in October 2012 conducted at the TVA Sequoyah Nuclear Plant.

2010-2012

Engineering Corrective Action Program Manager at Tennessee Valley Authority Manager of the Corrective Action Program (CAP) and Performance Improvement functions for the Watts Bar Engineering organization. Interfaced with other plant organizations to coordinate corrective action program functions including the corrective action program, trending reviews, benchmarking, and self assessments. Acted as the engineering representative for the CAP problem screening committee by providing technical insight and guarding the design basis of the plant, and chaired the Engineering Departmental Corrective Action Review Board to ensure quality CAP products.

Developed automated reporting tools for use within Watts Bar engineering as well as the Nuclear Power Group Fleet for management of CAP health and integration between the CAP and work management software by providing interfacing managers with key information to ensure that they could meet their goals and deadlines using IBM Cognos reporting authoring tools.

Guided the Engineering department CAP health at Watts Bar toward excellence while managing a steady increase in Problem Evaluation reports. This was evidenced by engineering CAP program health improving from consistently poor performance at Yellow and Red over the previous decade to the best sustainable performance at White to Green with continuous improvement by reducing the backlog of Problem Evaluation Reports and Actions, increasing engineer engagement, and improving causal analysis quality.

Robert Neil Cole 2

Professional Experience (cont'd)

2008-2010

Civil Design Engineer at Tennessee Valley Authority

Provided plant support regarding civil issues including Design Changes, Piping Stress Analysis meeting ASME code requirements for Class 2 and 3 piping systems, structural analysis & design, licensing document change requests, and owned the NUREG-0612 Control of Heavy Loads and temporary equipment programs at Watts Bar.

Provided engineering review/expertise and support of crane and rigging issues. Ensured site compliance with the NUREG-0612 Control of Heavy Loads program including review and approval of deviations within Critical Lift Zones and design of special lifting devices.

Mentored new engineers in the engineering graduate progression program to successfully fulfill requirements and obtain required qualifications. Assisted driving resolution of progression program discrepancies in order to ensure engineers could satisfactorily complete the program.

2005-2007

Systems Administrator at Pennant Foods Corporation

Administrator of Windows servers and clients, Exchange, SQL, and monitoring/virtualization solutions on Linux. Responsibilities also included maintaining and supporting various means of connectivity (DSL, dialup, VPN) between store locations and the internet/corporate intranet and remote banking locations via VPN.

Provided desktop support for approximately 50 users at the corporate locations, including software troubleshooting, recommendations, and upgrades. Software support included Microsoft Office, Great Plains accounting, and custom FoxPro solutions for food cost evaluation.

2004-2005

Consultant at Young and Mead Consulting

Provided support and software development (FoxPro) for various firms in food service, liquor sales, and railway production. Primary roles included supporting network and server (Windows) issues including Exchange configuration, backup, and maintenance tasks. Secondary roles included FoxPro development, point of sale interface design, generating client network and system documentation, mail server configuration and administration (Postfix/sendmail), and desktop support of clients on an as-needed basis.

Education, Licenses and Certifications

May 2013 Senior Reactor Operator Certification (ANSI 3.1, Expected), TVA-SQN/Hyperspring Dec. 2007 Engineer-In-Training Lic. 26514, Tennessee Department of Commerce and Insurance B.Sc. in Civil Engineering, The University of Tennessee at Knoxville

Skills and Associations

Engineering Skills: AutoCAD, MathCAD, Microstation, Structural Analysis, Piping Analysis, Corrective Action Program, Nuclear Power, Apparent Cause Analysis, Design Engineering, Plant Operations, Program Management, SRO Cert (ANSI/ANS 3.1), Cranes and Rigging, NUREG-0612

Technical Skills: Cognos Report Studio, Microsoft Office, Network Administration, Microsoft Windows, Mac OS X, SQL Querying, LATEX, Systems Administration, Desktop Support

Associations: ASCE, ASME, ANS, North American-Young Generation in Nuclear (NA-YGN)